It’s difficult not to admire the talent of a skilled musician.
很难不钦佩技艺精湛的音乐家的才华。
Whether it be a pianist, flautist or cellist, these individuals have shown dedication and passion over a long period of time to reach the highest levels of performance.
无论是钢琴家、长笛演奏家还是大提琴演奏家，这些人都凭借长期的付出与热爱，才达到了顶尖的演奏水准。
But they say it’s never too late to learn.
但人们常说，学习永远不嫌晚。
So what are the benefits, for both children and adults, in learning a musical instrument?
那么，学习一门乐器对儿童和成人而言，究竟有哪些益处呢？
Learning to play a musical instrument when growing up can improve hearing in adulthood.
年少时学习演奏乐器，有助于提升成年后的听力水平。
According to a study by Dr Nina Kraus, Professor of Neurobiology at Northwestern University in Illinois, US, children who played musical instruments were better at recognising different frequencies.
美国伊利诺伊州西北大学神经生物学教授妮娜·克劳斯博士的一项研究表明，学过乐器的儿童更善于分辨不同的音频。
This improved hearing skill carried over into later life with adults who had once played an instrument able to discern sounds of different pitches more easily.
这种提升后的听力技能会延续到日后的生活中，曾学过乐器的成年人能更轻松地辨别不同音高的声音。
And it could also have some academic benefits too.
此外，学习乐器对学业也有帮助。
A study conducted by the University of British Columbia found that students who engaged in music-related activities during grades 7-12 scored significantly higher in science, English and maths.
英属哥伦比亚大学的一项研究发现，在7至12年级期间参与过音乐相关活动的学生，在科学、英语和数学学科的成绩要显著更高。
And there are not just benefits to children.
学习乐器的益处并非只针对儿童。
Whether you choose to play the piano, pick or strum a guitar or learn a drumbeat, you could end up joining a band or orchestra.
无论你选择弹钢琴、拨弄吉他、扫弦，还是学习打鼓，最终都有可能加入一支乐队或管弦乐团。
This in turn could improve your social life, meeting other bandmates who are likeminded in their love of a good tune.
这进而能丰富你的社交生活，结识其他志同道合、同样热爱美妙旋律的乐队伙伴。
Learning an instrument can also give you a sense of achievement.
学习乐器还能带给你成就感。
Nailing that perfect chord is one way, but what if you got together with a bunch of friends and entered into a battle of the bands – and won?
弹出一组完美的和弦是一种成就，但如果你和一群朋友组队参加乐队大赛并夺冠，那种成就感又会是怎样的呢？
So, whether you’re looking to destress playing out some chords, or improve your grades at school, maybe taking up an instrument could help you.
所以，无论你是想通过弹奏和弦来减压，还是希望提高学业成绩，或许学习一门乐器都能帮到你。